Hana Belay

Web Developer

♣ Profile

I'm a passionate and hardworking developer with experience in building web applications and RESTful APIs for small-sized businesses and schools. My areas of expertise include Django, Django rest framework, React.js, and TailwindCSS. I also write excellent technical articles with clear direction and explanations to directed users.

Education

Software Engineering, Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar

September 2019 - Present

- · CGPA: 3.9/4.0
- · Anticipated Graduation Year: 2024

Projects

Django Registration/Login System

- It's written in Python Django, and Bootstrap for the frontend.
- Find the project on Github and a blog series about the project on DEV.

Recipe API

- A recipe sharing API built using **Django rest framework**.
- Find the project live on Heroku and source code on GitHub

Recipe App

- · Recipe sharing app built using React.js, Redux and TailwindCSS.
- Find the project live on Heroku and source code on GitHub

My Personal Website

• It's developed using React.js and TailwindCSS. Find it on Github

■ Employment History

Django Developer at Zede-Tech, Addis Ababa

October 2021 — February 2022

 Worked on the API for a digital bookkeeping record book called Dukka.

Full Stack Web Application Developer at Gebeya

October 2021 — Present

Extra-curricular activities

GDSC Core Team Member at GDSC Bahir Dar, Bahir Dar

January 2020 — Present

 As a GDSC core team member at Bahir Dar University, I'm currently participating in a project to build a forum for our university.

BDAC Volunteer at Bahir Dar American Corner, Bahir Dar

June 2021 — Present

Certification and Awards

- Google IT Support
- Al For Everyone

Details

Bahir Dar

Ethiopia

+251986003562

hanagetbel93@gmail.com

Links

Website

Linkedin

Github

DEV

Skills

Python

Django

React.js

JavaScript

TailwindCSS

Bootstrap

Web Development

Java

SQL

Algorithms and Data

Structures

Linux

Git

MySQL

Microsoft Office

Strengths

Team Work

Communication Skills

Ability to Learn Quickly

Critical Thinking